# Derek Quach

Seattle WA

■ 206-372-4149 | ■ derek.quach15@gmail.com | • dnqUW | • derek-quach-4b69a51aa/ | Portfolio

### Personal Profile

Technical writer of 2 years, software development of 4 years, IT tech of 2 years, and 5+ years writing for target audiences. English BA & Bio AA. Excellent: project management, programming, SEO/keyword research, verbal and writing skills. Has experience and familar with SSO, SDLC, REST API, JSON. Works WELL with developers, SMEs, software, and SSO in sprints.

## Skills

**Programming** Java, SQL, Markdown, HTML, CSS, JScript, Git, GitHub, (Click here for Certifications)

Technical Writing, Technical Documentation, User manuals, Agile framework, APIs, Java, SQL, HTML, JScript, Oxygen XML, Madcap

Flare, Confluence, MS Suite, Adobe suite, Yoast SEO, Microsoft suite, DaVinci Resolve, Data structures, Algorithms, Figma

**Soft Skills** Time Management, Teamwork, Problem-solving, Documentation, Friendly, Multi-tasking, Communication, Content Creation

## Work Experience\_

**Gunkustom** Cambridge, MA

Social Media Marketing Manager & Technical Writer

Jan 2024 - Present

- Utilized Confluence to maintain 15 internal documentation, standard operating procedures, tutorials, and training manuals.
- · Increased social media following by an average of 21% across all social media platforms. Crafted over 150 social media posts.
- · Maintained and optimized internal documentation to increase general audience readability by 20%.

Reston, VA

Bootcamp Software Engineer & Technical Writer

May 2023 - Sept 2023

- Aced all 93 (combined) Java and SQL coding labs, challenges, and mini-projects
- 100% completion & score on all assignments and labs. SQL queries, Big O, data structures, algorithms.
- Developed social media API application and corresponding technical documentation

**humanID** Cambridge, MA

Technical Writing Team Lead

2022 - 2023

2018 - 2020

Seattle, WA

- Maintained all tech writing standard operating procedures, tutorials, training manuals, and field documentation of our SaaS login
- Expanded blog's article count for technical audiences by 10% and optimized SEO score and web traffic by 15%
- · Led and delegated over 50 technical writing tasks and tracked three onboarding processes single-handedly

**humanID** Cambridge, MA

Technical Writing Intern 2022 - 2023

- 23% augmentation rate domain authority. Suitability for general audience average score from 80% to 90%
- · Utilized graphics to supplement clear and concise documentation. Surpassed expected quantity of deliverables
- Slashed documentation delivery time by 25% while working with software engineers & SME team

TQComputers INC.

Burien, WA

IT Technician

- Over 80 walk-in clients' devices (Windows laptops, desktops, printers & iOS tablets) restored to the desired functionality
- Researched, evaluated and recommended resolutions to business owners and end users

#### Education

### University of Washington

Bachelor of Arts: English

Highline College Des Moines, WA

Associate of Science: Biology

## **Current Projects**

#### **How to Build a Neural Network**

Self-interest Dec 2023 - Present

- Over 55 hours spent learning neural networks
- Java and python used as different methods to create the neural network
- Flappy Bird used as an example
- Technical Skills: Machine Learning, AI, Neural Networks, Backward Propagation.

JUNE 4, 2024